Okay, so now that I've shown you a
little bit more about how objects and
arrays can be stacked inside of each
other, I want to revisit the reduce
function. What I want to do is I want to
reduce this entire array with a lot of
arrays in it down to one object. That
object I want to have two objects inside
of it, an A team and a B team. Because
some of these superheroes are A team
superheroes and some of these
superheroes are B team superheroes. I
want to reduce it down so that it looks
like an object like this. So each object
is going to have an A. So this is the A
team and it's going to have a list of
members and it's going to be a list of
everyone's name that's a member. And
then it's going to be the total villains
that the members of that team caught.
Then I'm going to have the B team and
I'm going to list off their members and
the total villains that they caught. So
we can do this using a reduce function.
So the way we do this is we're going to
create our object. So I'll say let um
reduced
data or I'm actually going to call this
data by team equal and then what I want
to do is I want to access the justice
league and I want to reduce it. So
reduce takes a function. This function
can take in a previous value and a
current value and then it needs to do
some processing and then return a value.
So what I want to do is first the
current value is going to be an item
from this array. So if we want to grab
information about this array, notice I'm
storing their alias and I'm changing it
by their total villains and I need to
know which team they belong to. So I'm
going to dstructure
um the array that I grab out of Justice
League into variables so that my code's
a little more readable. So I don't care
about the first name. I don't care about
the last name. I do care about the
alias. Um,
I do need their number of villains. So,
Numville. And then I do need their team.
And I'm going to set that equal to
current. So, what this does is it
dstructures the array, pulls out alias,
number of villains, and their team. Now,
this previous object is eventually the
object that I'm going to return at the
end of it. So I want it to be an object
that can be accessed by this data by
team. So in other words, if this is an
object, the first thing I want to do is
I want to see if the team exists. So for
example, in this Justice League, I want
to see if there's already an A team and
if there's already a B team. So, I'm
going to do is I'm going to say if
team
is in
the previous object, meaning if by the
time we've gotten to this point in our
loop, if the object already exists, then
what are we going to do with it? If it
doesn't exist, then we want to create an
object that looks like this. So, how do
we do that? Well, we'll say if it
doesn't exist, then we want to go into
previous at the team position, and we
want to set it equal to an object.
What's going to be in that object? Well,
it needs a members
um key, which has an empty list. The
other thing it needs is a total
villain's key, and it's going to start.
And where do we want it to start? Well,
if it doesn't exist, in other words, if
we're adding Superman, then the first
thing we want to do is instead of
putting an empty list for members, we
want to put Superman in that list. Where
is Superman being stored? It's being
stored in this alias. So, we'll access
the alias. Okay, total villains. Do we
want to start it at zero or do we want
to start it at the number of villains
Superman caught? If this is our first
time accessing the object, then we just
want to set it to how many villains
Superman caught. And that is this numbum
vill right here.
So what we're saying is go into this
giant object here and see if A exists.
If it doesn't, create an object called
A. Inside of that object, create a
members key that stores an array and
start it with Superman. Create a total
villains and start it with however many
villains Superman caught, which in this
case is 12.
And then start the loop over.
Then grab the next team. Next person.
The next person is going to be Bruce
Wayne who's also on a team. Bruce Wayne
is on a team. So rather than creating
another A object, we just want to update
the A object that already exists.
And there are two things we want to do.
First, we want to add his alias into the
running list. And second, we want to
update the number of villains with his
villain count. So, what we're going to
do is we're going to go to
the previous object, access it by its
team position, and then inside of that
team,
we want to access its members.
And once we've done that, we can push in
our alias. So, what that does is it
comes to this members list, which
currently would only have Superman. And
on the next time through, it's going to
add Batman to that list. The other thing
we want to do is we want to update total
villains. So, we're going to go to the
previous
um object. We're going to access its
team position. We're going to access its
total villains position, and we're going
to increase it by Batman's number of
villains.
And once we're done, we need to return
the adjusted object.
Okay, so that probably looks pretty
complicated, but we're going to go put
in a breakpoint, and I'll walk you
through this line by line. So, let's
come over here to sources, and I'm going
to put a break point on this line right
here where we do our reduce. So, if we
reload,
we're about to run this Justice League
reducer, and I realized we actually have
a problem. So coming back over this
Justice League reducer is going to
access this as the first object unless
we want unless we tell it to start with
something else. So coming to this
reducer, I'm going to tell it to start
with an empty object. So we're going to
start with nothing and then we're slowly
going to build it. So coming over here,
we'll reload the page
and it's going to pause and we're about
to start our loop. So we're about to
assign previous and current. If we hit
next, previous is an object with no
properties, which makes sense. That's
what we told it to start with. Current
is our list. Clark, K, Superman, 12, and
a. If we hit next, we've dstructured it.
So alias is storing Superman. Number of
villains is storing 12. And team is
Superman is on the A team of the Justice
League. If so, we're going to see if A
is in our previous object. Right now,
our previous object has no properties.
So it's not. So we're going to skip to
the else statement and we're going to
create that property inside of previous
and we're going to give it an object
that has a members list and a total
villains. If we hit next now, if we
hover over previous, it has an A object.
Inside of that A object, it has a
members list. Inside of that members
list, it's storing Superman. The other
thing inside of the A object is total
villains, which are now 12. So, we're
going to hit return for the previous and
it's going to start our loop over. Okay,
what is in previous now? Well, it's the
thing that we just built.
What's in current now? It's Batman. So,
if we hit next, alias is Batman. number
of villains is 20 and the team is A. So
we're going to see if A is in the
previous object. It is. So we're going
to go into this if statement. So we hit
next and we're going to go into the
previous object at the A position and
we're going to access its members and
then we're going to push in Batman. So
we're going to go in here, open up
members, add Batman. So if we hit next
and we go back to the object, we can now
see that in members there is Superman
and Batman. The other thing we want to
do is we want to access the total
villains and increment them by 20.
So if we hit next now
inside of a we are storing that their
members are Superman and Batman and
total villains is now not a number.
Interesting.
That means I have written some code here
slightly wrong. So um and actually you
can see it there are two keys. So this
key is total villains with an I. This
key is total villains or villians and it
does not have an I. So I'm going to go
match the spelling here. Apologize for
that. and then this will work as we
expected.
All right. So, we'll reload the page.
We're starting. We're going to grab
Superman. So, previous is an object
that's empty. This is an array that
holds Clark Kent. We're seeing if his A
team is in the previous object. It's
not. So, we're going to hit next. We're
going to create it and we're going to
come back through. Okay, now we're
grabbing Batman. Um, we've got Batman,
number of villains that he caught, and
he's part of the A team. The A team is
in fact in this object. So, we're going
to drop in, and we're going to push
Batman into there. So, now we have an A
team object that has a members list that
has Superman and Batman inside of it.
The total villains right now is 12, but
we're going to update them with Batman's
20. If we hit next and we hover over
that previous object, if we open it up,
we can see that our total villains is
now 32. Now, we're going to return that
object and start our loop over. What is
in our previous object? Well, that a
object that we just built that stores
Superman and Batman. And the total
villains is 32. We're going to hit next.
And now we've got Wonder Woman who
caught 15 villains and is part of the A
team as well. So, we hit next. We push
Wonder Woman into the list. So now in
our a object we have a members list that
has Superman, Batman and Wonder Woman
and a total of 32 villains. If we hit
next and we return the previous um now
our previous object has an a team and
inside of that a team object there are
members. That members object is a list
which stores Superman, Batman, and
Wonder Woman and they've caught a total
of 47 villains.
So, I'm going to hit continue.
Oops, that actually continued all the
way through to the end of the code. So,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
come here to line 38, reload, and I'm
going to hover over data by team. And
you can see that it is an object that
has two objects inside of it, an A
object and a B object. In the A object,
it has a list of members of everyone on
the A team. And the total villains they
caught was 95. There's also a B object
and it has all of the members on the B
team and the total villains they caught
was 65.
And so by using reduce to return a
single item, meaning this object, we
could take this gigantic array with a
lot of information and crunch it down to
some very valuable numbers. Thanks for
watching.